<page title="Glacial Hikes">

<section class="post"><H2>Gamlin Crystal Springs</H2>
    <section class="text">    
        <p>The Gamlin Esker Trail traverses a long, high esker.  Eskers are steep-sided ridgelines 
        left by melting glaciers. The hike begins with an adventurous climb up the side of 
        the esker. Once atop, the hike becomes a leisurely trek along the wooded spine of the 
        esker. Hikers traversing the esker ridgeline are afforded fine views of Cow Pond Brook 
        flowing below, another remnant from the time of the glaciers. The Gamlin Esker Trail is a 
        habitat for nesting turtles, deer, and playful otters. Later in the hike, there is a 
        prominent wetland area, that has constant beaver activity.</p>
    </section>
    <section class="photos-map">
        <img height="350" width="350" src="images/gamlin-crystal-spring-esker-trail.jpg"/>        
        <div class="postmap" id="gamlin_springs"></div>
    </section>
    <section class="link">
        <a href="Media/Gamlin%20Crystal%20Spring%20Area%20Trail%20Map%20-%20Groton%20MA.pdf">Printable Map</a> 
            <br/>
        <a href="https://vimeo.com/129594586">Gift of the Glaciers Video</a>
            <br/>
        <a href="http://www.gctrust.org/archives/1782">Groton Conservation Trust Page</a> 
    </section> 
</section>
  
<section class="post"><H2>Groton Town Forest Kettle Hole Walk</H2>
    <section class="text">
        <p>Kettle holes are formed when large blocks of ice break off from a retreating glacier and become buried in sediment.  
        Eventually the block of ice melts leaving a depression called a kettle hole.
        The Groton Town Forest is one of the largest trail networks in Groton. This 
        network of trails is truly diverse and will suit the wishes of anyone. Whether 
        you want to go for a stroll on a welcoming day or tear it up on a mountain bike, 
        this property is for you. There is a scenic route that follows the Nashua River, 
        as well as an alluring trail that follows the old railroad tracks. A walk in the 
        Groton Town Forest is wonderful. As you let your worries and obligations fade 
        away, just enjoy the untouched beauty of nature. </p>
        <p>To enjoy The Groton Town Forest kettle holes it is recommended to take The Loop Trail.</p>
    </section>
    <section class="photos-map">        
        <div class="postmap" id="town_forest"></div></section>
    <section class="link">
        <a href="Media/Groton%20Town%20Forest%20Trail%20Map%20-%20Groton%20MA.pdf">Printable Map</a><br/>
        <a href="https://vimeo.com/129594586">Gift of the Glaciers Video</a>
    </section> 
</section>

<script>
    createSimpleMap('gamlin_springs',[42.6298,-71.5022],15,{ parking:[42.62489,-71.50248]});
    createSimpleMap('town_forest',[42.5906,-71.6073],14,{ parking:[42.59723,-71.60502]});
</script>

</page>